Przemyslaw Sanecki (b. 1977, PL)

132/7 Pleasance, EH8 9TL Edinburgh, UK Phone: +447706610649

> E-mail: <u>przemyslaw.sanecki@gmail</u> Web-site: <u>http://performism.org</u>

Motivation

My artistic carrier began from performance art in 1999 (a début at Galeria Entropia, Wroclaw, PL)

Since then, I have been active in many fields of fine arts. My works range from intense body art performance, through experimental electronics and live coding practise, to novel use of artificial intelligence as a medium of art.

My works have been presented both individually and during group shows at art institutions and festivals in Poland, Europe and USA, including Slingshot Festival, Galeria Stereo, Galeria Entropia, Zacheta National Gallery of Art, Center for Contemporary Art Ujazdowski Castle, Galeria Start, Sainsbury Centre for Visual Arts in Norwich, and Kunst-Werke in Berlin.

I was a member of music band KOT (together with Wojciech Bakowski and Piotr Bosacki).

I have a doctorate in Fine Arts and I am a qualified lecturer with 4yrs teaching experience at the graduate level.

My competencies also comprise a software development and consultancy in a wide range of modern technologies.

Education

2014	Doctor of Arts, University of Arts, Poznan, PL
2005	Master of Arts, Academy of Fine Arts, Wroclaw, PL

Professional Experience

2014-Present	Artist, programmer, and data analyst, freelance, Edinburgh, UK
2008-2014	Lecturer, University of Arts, Poznan, PL
2007-2008	Curator of collection, WRO Art Center, Wroclaw, PL

Selected performances, solo and group exhibitions

2015	"The Source of the Work of Art", Slingshot Media Festival, Athens, US-GA
2014	"Critical Machines", Mediation Art Biennial, Poznan, PL
	"The Source of the Work of Art", 2014, Gallery of University of Arts, Poznan, PL (solo)
2013	Live at Center for Contemporary Art Ujazdowski Castle, Warszawa, PL
2012	Access Art Fest, Wroclaw, PL "Gas chamber", Kontener Art, Poznan, PL, (with Robert B. Lisek and Gil Kuno)
	Live at Pawilon Nowa Gazownia, Poznan, PL
2011	ArtBazaar scene, 14 th WRO Media Biennial, Wroclaw, PL (as KOT)
2010	"Every step is taking me up", Galeria Stereo, Poznan, PL "Crash", BWA Awangarda, Wroclaw, PL

2009	"Heaven", Galeria Start, Warszawa, PL (solo)
2008	"Drop Point", Laznia CSW, Gdansk, PL (with Adam Krzysztofiak) "Kill All White People", Arsenal Gallery, Poznan, PL (solo) "Establishment", Center for Contemporary Art Ujazdowski Castle, Warszawa, PL
2007	Euro-Asia Art Festival, CK Zamek, Poznan, PL
2005	Diploma exhibition, Entropia Gallery, Wroclaw, PL (solo)

Grants

2011 Ministerial Grant for Young Researchers, Ministry for Science and Higher Education in Poland

Residencies

2008 Residency at Center for Contemporary Art Ujazdowski Castle, Warszawa, PL

Conferences:

2012 MutaMorphosis Conference, 2013, Prague, CZ

Publications and interviews

2015	Interview, in Peripheral ARTeries on-line magazine
2014	"Information as abstraction", doctoral thesis, advisor prof. Andrzej Syska, University of Arts, Poznan, PL
2012	"Creative coding for artists", textbook, University of Arts Poznan, PL
2011	Pamphlets, RitaBaum Magazine, Transhuman Edition, Wroclaw, PL
2008	Interview, in "We go far beyond", artistic book, Poznan, PL

Collections

2009-Present Works held in private collections in Poland, the United States, and Germany.

2008 Center for Contemporary Art Ujazdowski Castle, Warszawa, PL

Competencies

Languages	Polish (native), English (advanced), French (intermediate),, German (basic), Russian (basic)
Teaching	4yrs teaching experience at the graduate level (higher education in art).
experience	4915 teaching experience at the graduate level (higher education in art).
Programming	Python, Clojure, Java, Scala, Processing, Lisp, Octave, C, Pure Data, JavaScript,
languages	SuperCollider, and Ruby

Technical skills machine learning and artificial intelligence, statistics, natural language processing, 3d modelling, video editing and 3d modelling, digital publishing